# Peter Mwita IT Specialist

+254717384542 pmwita2017@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/peter-mwita github.com/pmwita

## **Professional Summary**

Dependable and goal-oriented IT Specialist with 5+ years of experience maintaining in-house IT systems and providing comprehensive customer support. At XYZ Global, saved 4 workhours a week for a team of 15 specialists through creating scripts to automate scheduled system patching.

## **Work History**

## **Senior IT Specialist**

XYZ Global, Nairobi, KE

Jan 2018-Present

- Maintained 250+ Windows computers and peripherals, including all configuring and monitoring. Worked with vendors to cut equipment costs by 20%.
- Installed 200+ desktop computers during a company-wide upgrade.
- Improved the overall network capabilities by 18% through designing and implementing new connectivity network configurations.
- Spearheaded hardware and software upgrade rollouts.

**Key achievement:** Wrote scripts to automate scheduled system patching. Saved 4 hours a week.

# **IT Support Specialist**

Zero Web, Nairobi, KE Dec 2015–Dec 2017

- Provided Help Desk-based IT phone support to end-users for a fastpaced web hosting firm, including troubleshooting, server support, and customer service.
- Maintained 15% above average customer satisfaction in post-call surveys. Used deep compassion and listening skills for the best customer experience.
- Became a trusted resource through high-level problem-solving skills.
  Solved customer issues with 12% more success than the company average.
- Kept 250 employees up and running on Windows 10.

## **Junior Desktop Support Engineer**

Calumcoro Medical, Nairobi, KE Jan 2014–Dec 2015

- Handled all desktop support issues in a high-volume manufacturing firm.
- Handled trouble tickets 25% faster than other desktop support engineers.
- Commended by management for exemplary troubleshooting skills.

### **Education**

BSc, Computer Science Multimedia University of Kenya, Nairobi, KE Nov 2017

## **Key Skills**

- System Administration
- Network Configuration
- Software Installation
- Troubleshooting
- Windows Environment
- Customer Service
- Technical Support

### **Certifications**

- 2016, CompTIA A+
- 2019, MS Server